Hi. So, this chap here,
مرحبا. إذن هذا الشّخص هنا
he thinks he can tell you the future.
يعتقد أنّه قادر على التّنبؤ بالمستقبل.
His name is Nostradamus, although here the Sun have
اسمه نوستراداموس، رغم أنّ مجلة ذا سان
made him look a little bit like Sean Connery. (Laughter)
جعلته يبدو كأنّه شان كونري.(ضحك)
And like most of you, I suspect, I don't really believe
وكمعظمكم، فأنا أشكّك، إنّني لا أصدّق
that people can see into the future.
أنّ النّاس يستطيعون الاطّلاع على المستقبل.
I don't believe in precognition, and every now and then,
أنا لا أؤمن بالعرافة، ومن حين إلى آخر،
you hear that somebody has been able to predict something that happened in the future,
نسمع عن شخص قادر على التّنبؤ بما سيحصل في المستقبل،
and that's probably because it was a fluke, and we only
وهذا ربما لأنّها كان ضربة حظّ، ونحن نسمع
hear about the flukes and about the freaks.
فقط عن ضربات الحظّ وعن الحالات الاستثنائية.
We don't hear about all the times that people got stuff wrong.
نحن لا نسمع أبداً عن الأخطاء التي حصلت لهؤلاء الناس.
Now we expect that to happen with silly stories
الآن نتوقّع أن يحدث ذلك مع القصص السخيفة
about precognition, but the problem is,
عن التنبؤ، ولكن المشكلة هي
we have exactly the same problem in academia
أنّ لدينا بالضبط نفس المشكلة في الأوساط الأكاديمية
and in medicine, and in this environment, it costs lives.
وعالم الطب، وفي هذه البيئة يكلّف الأمر حياة أشخاص.
So firstly, thinking just about precognition, as it turns out,
إذاً في البداية، فكرّ فقط بالتنبؤ، كما اتضح
just last year a researcher called Daryl Bem conducted
في السنة الماضية ، أجرى باحث اسمه داريل بيم
a piece of research where he found evidence
نموذج بحث حيث وجد أدلّة
of precognitive powers in undergraduate students,
على قوى التنبؤ عند طلاب المرحلة الجامعية،
and this was published in a peer-reviewed academic journal
وقد نُشرت في مجلة أكاديميّة بعد أن تمّت مراجعتها
and most of the people who read this just said, "Okay, well,
ومعظم الناس الذين قرأوا هذا قالوا "حسناً
fair enough, but I think that's a fluke, that's a freak, because I know
ربّما، لكن أعتقد أنّ هذه مجرد ضربة حظ، مصادفة،" لأنني اعلم
that if I did a study where I found no evidence
أنّني إذا قمت بدراسة و لم أجد أي دليل
that undergraduate students had precognitive powers,
أنّ الطلاب الجامعيين لديهم قوى تنبّؤية،
it probably wouldn't get published in a journal.
على الأغلب أنّه لن يتمّ نشرها بمجلّة.
And in fact, we know that that's true, because
وفي الواقع نحن نعلم ان هذه هي الحقيقة لأن
several different groups of research scientists tried
عدة مجموعات مختلفة من علماء البحوث حاولوا
to replicate the findings of this precognition study,
تبديل نتائج دراسة التنبؤ،
and when they submitted it to the exact same journal,
وعندما قدّموها لنفس المجلة
the journal said, "No, we're not interested in publishing
القائمين على المجلة قالوا "لا ، لسنا مهتمين بالنشر"
replication. We're not interested in your negative data."
نسخة مطابقة. نحن لا نقوم بنشر البيانات السلبيّة ."
So this is already evidence of how, in the academic
وهكذا فأن هذه دلالة معطاه لترينا ، أن المنشورات الأكاديمية سترينا
literature, we will see a biased sample of the true picture
نموذجا منحازا للصورة الحقيقية
of all of the scientific studies that have been conducted.
للدراسات العلمية التي أجريت .
But it doesn't just happen in the dry academic field of psychology.
ولكنها لا تحدث ببساطة في المجال الأكاديمي الجامد لعلم النفس.
It also happens in, for example, cancer research.
ولكنها تحدث على سبيل المثال في الأبحاث السرطانية .
So in March, 2012, just one month ago, some researchers
قبل شهر مضى، في مارس 2012، نشر بعض الباحثين
reported in the journal Nature how they had tried
في مجلة الطبيعة كيف حاولوا
to replicate 53 different basic science studies looking at
إيجاد 53 دراسة علمية مختلفة بالنظر
potential treatment targets in cancer,
إلى أهداف علاج محتملة في السرطان
and out of those 53 studies, they were only able
و من ال53 بحثا، تمكّنوا من
to successfully replicate six.
ايجاد 6 بنجاح
Forty-seven out of those 53 were unreplicable.
47 من ال 53 لم يتم انتاجهم
And they say in their discussion that this is very likely
و يقولون في مناقشتهم بأن ذلك محتمل جداً
because freaks get published.
لأن الاستثنائيات يتم نشرها
People will do lots and lots and lots of different studies,
سوف يقوم الناس بالكثير و الكثير من الدراسات المختلفة،
and the occasions when it works they will publish,
و في الحالات التي تنجح فيها سوف يتم نشرها
and the ones where it doesn't work they won't.
و في الحالات التي لا تنجح فيها لن يتم ذلك
And their first recommendation of how to fix this problem,
و في أول نصيحة حول كيفية حل المشكلة
because it is a problem, because it sends us all down blind alleys,
لأنها مشكلة، لأنها تقودنا الى طرقات مسدودة
their first recommendation of how to fix this problem
أول نصيحة لهم حول كيفية حل المشكلة
is to make it easier to publish negative results in science,
هي جعل نشر النتائج العلمية السلبية أسهل
and to change the incentives so that scientists are
و تغيير الحوافز حيث يتم تشجيع العلماء
encouraged to post more of their negative results in public.
لنشر نتائجهم السلبية أكثر بشكل علني
But it doesn't just happen in the very dry world
لكنها لا تحدث في العالم المحدود لأبحاث
of preclinical basic science cancer research.
السرطان الأساسية ماقبل التشخيص السريري فحسب
It also happens in the very real, flesh and blood
بل تحدث في الجسد و الدماء الحقيقية
of academic medicine. So in 1980,
للطب الأكاديمي. حيث في 1980،
some researchers did a study on a drug called lorcainide,
أجرى بعض الباحثين دراسة على عقار اسمه لوركانايد،
and this was an anti-arrhythmic drug,
و كان هذا العقار مضاد لعدم انتظام ضربات القلب
a drug that suppresses abnormal heart rhythms,
العقار الذي يعالج عدم انتظام ضربات القلب
and the idea was, after people have had a heart attack,
و الفكرة جاءت، بعد أن تعرض أشخاص لأزمة قلبية
they're quite likely to have abnormal heart rhythms,
كان من المحتمل جداً من أن يصابوا بعدم انتظام ضربات القلب
so if we give them a drug that suppresses abnormal heart
اذاً، لو أعطيناهم عقار يعالج عدم انتظام ضربات القلب
rhythms, this will increase the chances of them surviving.
هذا سوف يزيد فرصتهم بالبقاء على قيد الحياة
Early on its development, they did a very small trial,
في بدايات تطور هذا العقار، أجرو تجربة بسيطة جداً
just under a hundred patients.
أقل من مئة مريض
Fifty patients got lorcainide, and of those patients, 10 died.
تناول خمسين مريض جرعات من اللوركانايد، مات 10 منهم
Another 50 patients got a dummy placebo sugar pill
50 مريض آخرين تناولو البلاسيبو و هو عقار وهمي
with no active ingredient, and only one of them died.
لا يحوي أي مكون فعال، مات واحد منهم فقط
So they rightly regarded this drug as a failure,
حيث وجدو حقيقةً بأن هذا العقار فاشل
and its commercial development was stopped, and because
وتم ايقاف تطويره تجارياً
its commercial development was stopped, this trial was never published.
و بسبب توقيف تطويره التجاري، لم يعلن عن هذه التجربة
Unfortunately, over the course of the next five, 10 years,
لسوء الحظ، على مدى الخمس أو العشر سنوات القادمة
other companies had the same idea about drugs that would
لدى الشركات الأخرى نفس الفكرة عن العقاقير
prevent arrhythmias in people who have had heart attacks.
التي تعالج اضطراب ضربات القلب عند الأشخاص المصابين بأزمات قلبية
These drugs were brought to market. They were prescribed
تم احضار هذه العقارات الى السوق، تم وصفها
very widely because heart attacks are a very common thing,
بشكل واسع النطاق لأن الأزمات القلبية هي شيء شائع
and it took so long for us to find out that these drugs
قد أخذنا وقت طويل لنجد بأن هذه العقاقير
also caused an increased rate of death
أيضا قد سببت ازدياد معدل الوفاة
that before we detected that safety signal,
كان ذلك قبل أن نكتشف مؤشر السلامة هذا
over 100,000 people died unnecessarily in America
أكثر من مئة ألف شخص توفوا بدون سبب حقيقي في أمريكا
from the prescription of anti-arrhythmic drugs.
بسبب وصفة عقار مضاد اضطراب ضربات القلب
Now actually, in 1993,
في الواقع الآن، في عام 1993
the researchers who did that 1980 study, that early study,
الباحثين الذين أجروا دراسة في عام 1980، تلك الدراسة المبكرة
published a mea culpa, an apology to the scientific community,
نشروا اعتراف بالخطأ، اعتذار الى الوسط العلمي
in which they said, "When we carried out our study in 1980,
حيث قالوا ، " عندما نفذنا دراستنا في عام 1980،
we thought that the increased death rate that occurred
اعتقدنا بأن معدل الوفاة الذي حصل
in the lorcainide group was an effect of chance."
في المجموعة التي تناولت اللوركانايد كان نتيجة صدفة."
The development of lorcainide was abandoned for commercial reasons,
تم اهمال تطوير اللوركانايد لأسباب تجارية
and this study was never published;
و لم يتم نشر هذا الدراسة أبداً
it's now a good example of publication bias.
انها مثال جيد ا الآن للتحيز في النشر
That's the technical term for the phenomenon where
هذا هو المصطلح التقني لهذه الظاهرة
unflattering data gets lost, gets unpublished, is left
حيث أن المعلومات الغير مرغوب فيها تضيع، لا تنشر، متروكة
missing in action, and they say the results described here
ضائعة في الحدث، و يقولون بأن النتائج المشروحة هنا
"might have provided an early warning of trouble ahead."
ربما كانت قد أعطت تحذير مبكر للمشكلة القادمة
Now these are stories from basic science.
الآن هذه القصص من العلوم الأساسية
These are stories from 20, 30 years ago.
هنا قصص من 20، 30 عام سبقت
The academic publishing environment is very different now.
ان بيئة النشر الأكاديمي مختلفة الآن
There are academic journals like "Trials," the open access journal,
يوجد مجلات مثل "ترايلز"، مجلة متاحة للجميع
which will publish any trial conducted in humans
التي ستنشر أي تجربة أجريت على البشر
regardless of whether it has a positive or a negative result.
بغض النظر عن النتائج اذا كانت سلبية أو ايجابية
But this problem of negative results that go missing in action
لكن مشكلة النتائج السلبية الضائعة في الحدث
is still very prevalent. In fact it's so prevalent
هي أمر شائع، في الواقع هي أمر شائع كثيراً
that it cuts to the core of evidence-based medicine.
انها تدخل في صميم الطب القائم على الأدلة
So this is a drug called reboxetine, and this is a drug
هذا عقار يدعى ريبوكسيتين، و هو عقار
that I myself have prescribed. It's an antidepressant.
قمت بوصفه بنفسي، هو عقار مضاد للاكتئاب
And I'm a very nerdy doctor, so I read all of the studies
بما أني شخص مهووس بالدراسة، فقد قرأت ما استطعت من الدراسات
that I could on this drug. I read the one study that was published
حول هذا العقار، قرأت احدى الدراسات المنشورة
that showed that reboxetine was better than placebo,
و التي أظهرت أن الريبوكسيتين كان أفضل من البلاسيبو
and I read the other three studies that were published
و قرأت ثلاثة دراسات أخرى قد تم نشرها
that showed that reboxetine was just as good as any other antidepressant,
التي قد أظهرت بأن الريبوكسيتين هو عقار جيد مثل أي عقار مضاد للاكتئاب
and because this patient hadn't done well on those other antidepressants,
و لأن هذا المريض لم يتحسن على عقار مضاد الاكتئاب الآخر
I thought, well, reboxetine is just as good. It's one to try.
ظننت، حسناً، بأن الريبوكسيتين هو عقار جدير بالتجريب
But it turned out that I was misled. In fact,
لكن الأمور اتضحت بأني قد ضُللت
seven trials were conducted comparing reboxetine
تم اجراء سبع تجارب لمقارنة الريبوكسيتين
against a dummy placebo sugar pill. One of them
مع البلاسيبو العقار الوهمي. كانت نتيجة تجربة واحدة
was positive and that was published, but six of them
ايجابية حيث تم نشرها، لكن ستة من التجارب
were negative and they were left unpublished.
كانت سلبية و لم يتم نشرها
Three trials were published comparing reboxetine
تم نشر ثلاثة تجارب لمقارنة الريبوكسيتين
against other antidepressants in which reboxetine
مع عقار مضاد اكتآب آخر، فكان الريبوكسيتين
was just as good, and they were published,
جيد، فتم نشرها
but three times as many patients' worth of data was collected
لكن في ثلاث مرات تم جمع معلومات مهمة من المرضى
which showed that reboxetine was worse than
حيث أظهرت بأن الريبوكسيتين كان أسوأ
those other treatments, and those trials were not published.
من العقاقير الأخرى، لم يتم نشر هذه التجارب
I felt misled.
أحسست أنّه تمّ تضليلي.
Now you might say, well, that's an extremely unusual example,
ربما تقول الآن، حسناً، هذا مثال غير اعتيادي تماماً
and I wouldn't want to be guilty of the same kind of
لم أرد أن أكون مذنباً بنفس صنف
cherry-picking and selective referencing
انتقاء و المراجع المنتقاه
that I'm accusing other people of.
التي أتهم الآخرين بها
But it turns out that this phenomenon of publication bias
لكنه يتضح بأن ظاهرة التحيز في النشر هذه
has actually been very, very well studied.
قد تم دراستها بشكل جيد جداً للغاية
So here is one example of how you approach it.
و هنا تجد مثال حول كيفية التعامل معها
The classic model is, you get a bunch of studies where
النموذج التقليدي هو، أنك تحصل على مجموعة من الدراسات
you know that they've been conducted and completed,
حيث أنك تعرف أنه قد تم اجراؤها و اتمامها
and then you go and see if they've been published anywhere
بعد ذلك ترى ما اذا تم نشرها بمكان ما
in the academic literature. So this took all of the trials
في المنشورات الأكاديمية. اذاً تطلَب ذلك كل هذه التجارب
that had ever been conducted on antidepressants
التي تم اجراؤها على العقاقير المضادة الاكتئاب
that were approved over a 15-year period by the FDA.
و التي تم الموافقة عليها منذ 15 عام من قبل ال FDA
They took all of the trials which were submitted to the FDA as part of the approval package.
اعتبروا كل التجارب التي تم تقديمها ل FDA كجزء من عملية الموافقة
So that's not all of the trials that were ever conducted on these drugs,
لم يكن ذلك كل التجارب التي قد أجريت على هذه العقاقير
because we can never know if we have those,
لأنه لا يمكننا أن نعرف اذا كان لدينا ذلك
but it is the ones that were conducted in order to get the marketing authorization.
لكنها التجارب التي طبقت للحصول على ترخيص للتسويق
And then they went to see if these trials had been published
و بعدها ذهبوا للتأكد ما اذا تم نشر هذه التجارب
in the peer-reviewed academic literature. And this is what they found.
في المنشورات الأكاديمية المنقحة ، و هذا ما تم التوصل له
It was pretty much a 50-50 split. Half of these trials
كانت التجارب الى حد كبير منقسمة الى 50-50 . نصف التجارب
were positive, half of them were negative, in reality.
كانت ايجابية، و نصفها الآخر سلبية، حقيقةً.
But when they went to look for these trials in the peer-reviewed academic literature,
لكن عندما أرادو البحث عن هذه التجارب في المنشورات المنقحة
what they found was a very different picture.
ما وجدوه كان صورة مختلفة تماما.
Only three of the negative trials were published,
فقط ثلاثة من النتائج السلبية تم نشرها
but all but one of the positive trials were published.
لكن واحدة من النتائج الايجابية تم نشرها
Now if we just flick back and forth between those two,
اذا قمنا بحركة سريعة الى الأمام و الى الوراء بين النتيجتين
you can see what a staggering difference there was
ستجدوا اختلاف مذهل بين
between reality and what doctors, patients,
الحقيقة وما يمكن للأطباء، و المرضى
commissioners of health services, and academics
و مفوضي الخدمات الصحية، و الأكاديميين
were able to see in the peer-reviewed academic literature.
معرفته من المنشورات الأكاديمية المنقحة
We were misled, and this is a systematic flaw
لقد تم تضليلنا، و هذا هو الخلل المنهجي
in the core of medicine.
في صميم الطب
In fact, there have been so many studies conducted on
في الحقيقة، كان يوجد العديد من الدراسات المطبقة على
publication bias now, over a hundred, that they've been
التحيز في النشر الآن، فوق المئة دراسة كان قد
collected in a systematic review, published in 2010,
تم جمعها في مراجعة منهجية قد نشرت في 2010
that took every single study on publication bias
أحاط ذلك كل دراسة على حدة حول التحيز في النشر
that they could find.
كانوا قد تمكنوا من ايجادها
Publication bias affects every field of medicine.
التحيز في النشر يؤثر كل مجال من مجالات الطب
About half of all trials, on average, go missing in action,
حوالي نصف التجارب، كمعدل وسطي، تضيع بين الاجراءات
and we know that positive findings are around twice as likely
نحن نعرف أن احتمال نشر النتائج الايجابية هو ضعف
to be published as negative findings.
احتمال نشر النتائج السلبية
This is a cancer at the core of evidence-based medicine.
يعد ذلك بمثابة مرض السرطان الذي يصيب صميم الطب القائم على الأدلة
If I flipped a coin 100 times but then
اذا قمت بتجربة على نقد معدني مئة مرة لكن فيما بعد
withheld the results from you from half of those tosses,
قمت بحجب نتائج نصف الرميات عنكم
I could make it look as if I had a coin that always came up heads.
قمت بجعل النقد المعدني و كأنه يظهر دائماً الرؤوس
But that wouldn't mean that I had a two-headed coin.
لكني لم أقصد بأنه لدي نقد معدني برأس على الوجهين
That would mean that I was a chancer
سوف يعني ذلك بأني محظوظ
and you were an idiot for letting me get away with it. (Laughter)
و أنتم أغبياء لأنكم سمحتوا لي بأن أنجو بذلك. (ضحك)
But this is exactly what we blindly tolerate
لكن هذا تماماً ما نتسامح به بصورة عمياء
in the whole of evidence-based medicine.
في عموم الطب القائم على الأدلة
And to me, this is research misconduct.
و أنا أعتبر أن هذا البحث قد أسيئ تطبيقه
If I conducted one study and I withheld
اذا أجريت احدى الدراسات و حجبت
half of the data points from that one study,
نصف معلومات تلك الدراسة
you would rightly accuse me, essentially, of research fraud.
يمكنك بحق بأن تتهمني، أساساً، بتزوير البحث
And yet, for some reason, if somebody conducts
و الى الآن، لسبب ما، اذا قام شخص ما
10 studies but only publishes the five that give the result that they want,
ب عشر دراسات لكنه قام بنشر الخمس نتائج التي أعطت النتيجة المرجوة
we don't consider that to be research misconduct.
لا نعتبر ذلك اساءة للبحث
And when that responsibility is diffused between
و عندما تنتشر هذه المسؤولية بين
a whole network of researchers, academics,
كامل مجموعة الباحثين و الأكاديميين
industry sponsors, journal editors, for some reason
وقطاع الصناعة، ومحرري المجلات، لسبب ما
we find it more acceptable,
نتقبلها بشكل أكبر
but the effect on patients is damning.
لكن الأثر على المرضى واضح
And this is happening right now, today.
و هذا ما يحصل الآن، اليوم
This is a drug called Tamiflu. Tamiflu is a drug
يدعى هذا العقار تاميفلو. و هو عقار
which governments around the world have spent billions
قد أنفقت عليه الحكومات حول العالم المليارات
and billions of dollars on stockpiling,
و المليارات من الدولارات على التخزينمن الدولارات على تخزينه
and we've stockpiled Tamiflu in panic,
و قمنا بتكديس عقار التاميفلو متخوفين
in the belief that it will reduce the rate of complications of influenza.
معتقدين بأنه يخفض نسبة مضاعفات الانفلوانزا
Complications is a medical euphemism for pneumonia
مضاعفات هي تخفيف لمصطلح طبي هو الالتهاب الرئوي
and death. (Laughter)
و الموت. (ضحك)
Now when the Cochrane systematic reviewers
عندما قام المراجعين المنهجيين للمعلومات الطبية
were trying to collect together all of the data from all
بمحاولة جمع كل معلومات
of the trials that had ever been conducted on whether Tamiflu actually did this or not,
التجارب التي قد أجريت على التاميفلو ما اذا فعل هذا أم لا
they found that several of those trials were unpublished.
وجدو أن العديد من هذه التجارب لم تنشر
The results were unavailable to them.
لم تكن النتائج متاحة لهم
And when they started obtaining the writeups of those trials through various different means,
و عندما بدأوا بالحصول على نصوص التجارب من خلال عدة وسائل
through Freedom of Information Act requests, through
من خلال قانون الحرية في الحصول على المعلومات،
harassing various different organizations, what they found was inconsistent.
من خلال ازعاج العديد من المؤسسات المختلفة، ما وجدوه كان متضارب
And when they tried to get a hold of the clinical study reports,
و عندما سعوا للحصول على تقارير الدراسة السريرية
the 10,000-page long documents that have
كان لدى الوثائق ذات العشرة آلاف صفحة
the best possible rendition of the information,
أفضل مصدر ممكن للمعلومات
they were told they weren't allowed to have them.
حيث قيل لهم بأنه غير مسموح لهم بالحصول عليها
And if you want to read the full correspondence
و اذا أردت قراءة المراسلات الكاملة
and the excuses and the explanations given by the drug company,
و الأعذار و الشروحات التي أعطتها شركة العقار
you can see that written up in this week's edition
يمكنك مشاهدة ذلك في اصدار هذا الاسبوع
of PLOS Medicine.
من مجلة "بلوس ميديسين".
And the most staggering thing of all of this, to me,
و الشيء الأكثر دهشة بالنسبة لي من كل هذا
is that not only is this a problem, not only do we recognize
هو أنه لا يعتبر ذلك مشكلة فحسب، لا نكتشف فقط أن
that this is a problem, but we've had to suffer fake fixes.
ذلك يشكّل مشكلة، لكننا عانينا من الحلول الوهمية
We've had people pretend that this is a problem that's been fixed.
قابلنا أشخاص قد ادعوا أنه قد تم حل المشكلة
First of all, we had trials registers, and everybody said,
أولاً، كان لدينا موثقي تجارب، و الكل قال
oh, it's okay. We'll get everyone to register their trials, they'll post the protocol,
حسناً، سوف نجعل الجميع يوثقون تجاربهم، سوف ينشرون البروتوكول
they'll say what they're going to do before they do it,
سوف يقولون ماذا سوف يفعلون قبل أن يقوموا بأي شيء
and then afterwards we'll be able to check and see if all the trials which
فيما بعد سوف نتمكن من أن نلقي نظرة على كل التجارب التي
have been conducted and completed have been published.
قد أجريت بشكل كامل و تم نشرها
But people didn't bother to use those registers.
لكن لم يكلف الناس أنفسهم باستخدام هذه السجلات
And so then the International Committee of Medical Journal Editors came along,
و بعد ذلك تدخلت اللجنة الدولية لمحرري المجلات الطبية
and they said, oh, well, we will hold the line.
و قالوا، أوه، حسناً سوف نقوم بالتنظيم
We won't publish any journals, we won't publish any trials,
لن ننشر أي مجلة، لن ننشر أي تجربة
unless they've been registered before they began.
مالم يتم تسجيلها قبل بدئها.
But they didn't hold the line. In 2008, a study was conducted
لكنهم لم يقوموا بالمتابعة. في 2008 تم اجراء دراسة
which showed that half of all of trials published by journals
أظهرات بأن نصف التجارب التي تم نشرها من قبل المجلات
edited by members of the ICMJE
التي تم تحريرها من قبل أعضاء في ICMJE " اللجنة الدولية لمحرري المجلات الطبية "
weren't properly registered, and a quarter of them weren't registered at all.
لم تكن مسجلة بشكل صحيح، و ربع هذه التجارب لم تسجل قط
And then finally, the FDA Amendment Act was passed
و فيما بعد أخيراً، تم تمرير قانون التعديل من قبل FDA " ادارة العقاقير و الأغذية"
a couple of years ago saying that everybody who conducts
منذ سنتين مشيرة الى أن كل من قام باجراء
a trial must post the results of that trial within one year.
تجربة يتوجب عليه أن ينشر النتائج خلال عام واحد
And in the BMJ, in the first edition of January, 2012,
و في BMJ " المجلة الطبية البريطانية" ، في العدد الصادر في يناير 2012
you can see a study which looks to see if people kept
يمكنكم مشاهدة دراسة تقوم على متابعة ما اذا كان الأشخاص قد التزموا
to that ruling, and it turns out that only one in five
بذلك القانون، بدى أن واحد فقط من أصل خمسة
have done so.
قد التزم بذلك
This is a disaster.
هذه كارثة.
We cannot know the true effects of the medicines
لا يمكننا أن نعرف الآثار الحقيقية للأدوية
that we prescribe if we do not have access
التي نقوم بوصفها ما لم يكن لدينا طريقة للوصول
to all of the information.
الى كامل المعلومات
And this is not a difficult problem to fix.
وهذه ليست مشكلة صعبة الحلّ.
We need to force people to publish all trials
علينا أن نجبر النّاس على نشر كل التجارب
conducted in humans, including the older trials,
التي تمّ إجراؤها على البشر، حتّى القديمة منها،
because the FDA Amendment Act only asks that you publish the trials conducted after 2008,
لأن قانون التعديل الصادر عن FDA يطلب فقط نشر التجارب المجراة بعد 2008
and I don't know what world it is in which we're only
أنا لا أعلم ماهو العالم الذي نقوم فيه
practicing medicine on the basis of trials that completed in the past two years.
بممارسة الطب على أساس التجارب التي اكتملت في العامين السابقين فقط.
We need to publish all trials in humans,
علينا أن نقوم بنشر كل التجارب المجراة على البشر،
including the older trials, for all drugs in current use,
حتى التجارب القديمة لكل العقاقير المستخدمة في الوقت الحالي،
and you need to tell everyone you know
و عليك أن تخبر كلّ الأشخاص الذين تعرفهم
that this is a problem and that it has not been fixed.
أنّ هذا مشكل وأنّه لم يتمّ حلّه بعد.
Thank you very much. (Applause)
شكرا جزيلا لكم. (تصفيق)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)